<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Captains-log</title>
    <description>:rocket: A responsive Jekyll theme based on my personal internet site</description>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 14:09:10 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 14:09:10 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>We are making a game, oh boi</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;let-the-games-begin&quot;&gt;Let the games begin&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Figured, I’ll put it here publicly (as public as a personal blog gets) as a silent reminder to myself to proceed further :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spend my life doing web for work and, often, pleasure. At the same time, I love playing video games, exploring what indie game devs are up to. Making a game was always something i wanted to do; besides, it’s nice to switch your brains from one activity to another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SO HERE WE COME! &lt;a href=&quot;http://sosedoff.com/&quot;&gt;@sosedoff&lt;/a&gt; is handling codes and i’m in charge of models. And we hope to figure the rest as we go :) It’s a side quest 👹 , so it’s going slow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gameplay&quot;&gt;Gameplay&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to share the plot or a gameplay (so EA won’t steal it). But meet Derek! He is flat for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/derek.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;blender-3d&quot;&gt;Blender 3D&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last time i did something 3D-realted was in college when I was building geometry for &lt;a href=&quot;cfd&quot;&gt;CFD&lt;/a&gt; modeling. I didn’t not make anything complex - models of pipes and square cavities were the tops. Thought, class I took 4 years ago while in grad school on &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Iterative_method&quot;&gt;iterative&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multigrid_method&quot;&gt;multigrid methods&lt;/a&gt; definetelly helped - i know that meshes exist 😬&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As any other complex software, it’s practically impossible to operate Blender 3D without use of hot keys. I do not have numpad and it slows me down even more, since switching the views is binded to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either way, here is a level map :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/derek-map.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned 🤖.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 14:28:59 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/2016/04/17/we-are-making-a-game/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/2016/04/17/we-are-making-a-game/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Animated interfaces are hot!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This post is located on &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.prototypr.io/animated-interfaces-are-hot-f0dc5dd6e329#.l3j9n5het&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 14:28:59 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/2016/04/10/animations-are-hot/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/2016/04/10/animations-are-hot/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Look ma, first post</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;dear-diary&quot;&gt;Dear Diary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog is a place for all my weird projects and web (or else) experiments that don’t fit into my main &lt;a href=&quot;http://masha.space&quot;&gt;portfolio&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mashasafina&quot;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://dribbble.com/mashasafina&quot;&gt;dribbble&lt;/a&gt; or my head, but shouldn’t just disappear in the abyss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll try to share more of my processes &amp;amp; thoughts to expose my human personality on the Internet, so you, people, know - i’m &lt;strong&gt;not a bot&lt;/strong&gt;. Or am I? &lt;strong&gt;Subscribe to my blog to find out!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, I’ll use this place as an attempt to systematize my chaotic mess of brain activity &amp;amp; practice my writing (turns out I love to write). Let’s bring order to the Universe! (nothing is in order, btw)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;outro&quot;&gt;Outro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;👇 If you would like to &lt;s&gt;see something&lt;/s&gt; say something - email me! DM! I’m very Internet social. Just, please, don’t call me on the phone.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2016 13:28:59 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/2016/04/08/look-ma-first-post/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/2016/04/08/look-ma-first-post/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
